hello welcome to another video of cod
snippet in this video we are going to
look into another important topic which
belongs to Spring data jpa so we have
already seen spring data jpa in last few
videos right we have also seen the types
of repositories that we have inside
spring data jpa now in this video we are
going to look into one of the important
concept inside spring data jpa that is
spring data jpa relationships that means
whenever multiple entities are coming
into picture inside your application
then how they are interrelated with each
other and how that can be implemented by
using spring data jpa so we are going to
look into very exciting stuff in this
video so let's get started without
wasting any time this is going to be a
fun video so sit back relax and enjoy
the show let me bring up the agenda over
here so basically spring data jpa
relationships right so until now we have
seen spring data jpa introduction we
have understood this jdbc RM jpa in the
first video in the second video we have
seen the architecture and entity life
cycle right and in the third video we
have seen spring data jpa implementation
right so we have seen this crude
repository jpa repository paging and
sorting repository apart from that we
have seen list crude repositories as
well along with list paging and sorting
repository right so this is basically
the update that we have in recent
version of our string data right so we
have understood everything we have seen
the implementation part as well so if
you haven't watched the previous videos
yet I will recommend you to go ahead and
watch those because it is kind of a
prerequisite of this video and in this
video we are going to look into spring
data jpa relationships we will see what
exactly is relationship when we say
relationship how we can Define the
relationship between the two entities
right after that we will see there are
multiple types of relationships then we
will see what are the types for example
we have one to one we have one to many
many to one many to many right so we
have these four right so we will
understand all of them with example and
we will also see how we can Implement
that inside our code right so by using
annotations we have various annotations
and while looking into this multiple
Concepts will come into picture for
example cascet deletes cascading and
multiple annotations also will come into
picture so all those things we are going
to look into in this video so that is
basically a simple agenda of this
particular video so let's get started so
before getting started with
relationships let's see what we have in
hand and what we have created in last
our videos right last few videos so if I
go over here so in the last video we
have implemented applicant management
system right so we have one entity only
one entity which is basically applicant
right so applicant is a person who is
going to apply for a job to this system
right after that here we had a simple
controller right so here if you see we
have applicant controller so we
implemented few of our apis over here
then we have this particular service
over here where is the service service
should be here so applicant service
right which is talking to our repository
so if you see over here we have seen
three type of repositories right we have
applicant crude repository right we have
applicant jpa repository and paging and
sorting repository right so in this
video we are going to build our
application on top of this we are going
to add few entities we are going to add
more and more repositories right so so a
lot more stuff will come into picture
over here right so let's get started
with relationships right now let's say
here in this application we have
applicant right so applicant is
basically one entity that we have right
now as we have only one entity inside
our application we cannot really Define
the relationship right so when we say
relationship relationship is basically
the way by using which two entities are
associated with each other right the way
they are related to each other right so
that is basically relationship between
entities so there should be at least two
entities to Define relationship right so
let's define another entity over here
right so let me just create another
entity let's say we have resume right so
resume is basically each applicant will
have resume right now let's say I an
applicant right so when I apply on the
application management system I can only
upload One resume right I cannot upad 10
rumes and ask them to select one for me
right we cannot do that we can only
upload one resum right when we talk
about resume entity one applicant can
only have one resume so that is how we
can Define the relation between
applicant and resum right let me write
some entity relationship diagram so
there is something called as entity
relationship diagram and it looks
something like
this so here if you see this is
basically our applicant table so this
guy will Define everything all the
fields that we have inside our applicant
table and we have a resume table so this
is let's say another table which is a
resume table and which have its own
Fields right so these are basically
entities so this is my entity and this
is my other entity basically over here
right now how they are related to each
other so that is something which we can
Define right how we can Define now that
can be defined by using some arrows
right so it's kind of a lines between
these two right if you are aware of
entity relationship diagram then you
might be aware of it already if you are
not aware then I can highlight it over
here right now here this applicant ID is
basically this applicant ID which is a
foreign key inside your resume right so
as I already mentioned one applicant can
only have one resume right one applicant
cannot have multiple resumés over here
right and one resume will be associated
with one applicant right so it's kind of
a one to one mapping right so when we
say type of relationships this
association between two entities can be
seg ated into these parts right so as we
have seen one to one is one type right
so there is one to many many to one many
to many right so these are basically the
type of relationships that we have over
here right so here applicant and resume
will have one to one mapping because one
applicant can have exactly one resume
right now how we can Define it in ER
diagram let me show you so here one
applicant one applicant over here can
have only one resume so here if you see
this is a straight line we are drawing
and here we are defining that one
applicant can have only one resume so
this ID is basically primary key inside
your resum table right so that is how we
can Define it so again one applicant can
have one resum so that is how we are
defining it inside our ER diagram right
so that is basically one: one mapping
right so as we are looking into one to
one mapping let's first implement this
scenario as well right so let's go back
over here inside our intell ID and as
you can see over here we already have
applicant right now we need to add one
more entity which is resume right so
let's add it first so what I'll do I'll
just add a new Java class let's name it
as
resume and I will just create this class
let me just mark it as a entity as this
guy will be our entity I will just add a
couple of fields over here first will be
ID right so usually first will be ID let
me just add a long ID over here let me
just add a long ID over here I will mark
it as at theate ID we add one more
annotation that is generated value so
that it is auto incremented right and I
will add a strategy over here and let's
say strategy is Generation type. Auto
right so what is strategy and everything
we have already covered as a part of
last video you might be aware of it
already right so resum we have let's say
some content right so content or let's
say the resume is saved inside some file
storage and we are giving that file
storage link or something over here
right now as we have seen over here that
that resume have applicant ID which is a
foreign key of your applicant right so
what we will do we will add a field over
here in resume that is basically
applicant right so what I will do I will
say private and I will say
applicant and applicant right so this is
basically the applicant resume will be
Associated to right so I will convert
this guy also to private encapsulation
right so applicant we have added over
here but we need to Define that this is
basically a foreign key that means the
ID inside applicant this particular ID
will be foreign key for our resume class
right so in order to do that what we
need to do is we can make use of join
column annotation right so join column
right the join column is basically a
notation that can be used in order to
add the foreign key inside your class
right so here I'm adding a foreign key
for this particular object right so we
need to add some kind of key name over
here right what we'll do we'll add let's
say applicant ID right so applicant ID
is basically the foreign key for your
applicant table right so if you see over
here we have added this applicant ID
over here right so what we can do we can
add it in camel case as well right so
applicant ID right so this applicant ID
will be saved inside a database when we
actually Sav the applicant and we can
add one more field that is nullable
nullable means this column cannot be
null when you add cant inside your
resume right so that is basically not
null constraint that we have in SQL
right so similar stuff over here right
so that is basically join column so here
when we actually look the table this
field will be replaced by applicant ID
right which will be stored inside your
database right and whenever we F or save
the data it will be automatically
converted to app entity so it is kind of
a join between these two column right so
jpa will form this query automatically
so we don't need to create all these
queries spring data will create
everything for us right and now about
the relationship we need to define the
relationship over here right so we can
make use of annotation one to one right
so one to one right so one to one means
one applicant is associated with one
resume like that right this annotation
will actually tell jpa that this
particular entity have one to one
mapping with your other entity right and
jpa will use this annotation to set up
similar kind of relationship while it
creates the query or creates the table
right so that is basically easily you
can map these two tables by using one to
one mapping right right so in order to
save some time I have added some code
over here so first of all I have added
these Getters and Setters over here in
the entity in a resume entity right
after that I'm creating a controller in
order to add the resume right so here
I'm creating a post mapping where I'm
taking application ID and along with
that I'm taking a request body resume as
well for this particular applicant ID
our resume will be added right and after
that I have created this particular
service request mapping where I have
added one function which will first find
the applicant by using applicant ID that
we are getting and after that we will
just add that particular applicant ID to
resume and save the resume right if it
is not found then we will will just
return this error that applicant is not
found with that particular ID right and
that's it and apart from that I have
added this resume repository which is
kind of a jpa reposit right simple
dimple stuff right now what we can do
let me just rerun this application over
here let's see what happens and let me
bring up my Postman right so first of
all what we are going to do is we are
going to add one applicant right so we
have this mangalam Shu over here so what
we will do we will just send and this
should add one applicant right as usual
stuff now what we'll do we'll just
create another API so this is the API
that I have added so here what I'm doing
/ API SL one that is one is basically
the applicant ID of the applicant that
we have added right that we are having
resume which is basically our this
particular end point over here applicant
id/ resume right now here what we are
doing we are just adding a Content this
is basically a dummy string I'm giving
over here now if I send this then we are
getting a response we are getting id1 we
are getting this content and the
respective applicant is populated over
here right now what we can do over here
is let me just go over here and let's
log into database right so how to log
into database we have seen it multiple
times isn't it so we'll just go and log
into our H2 console over here password
should be password let's try to connect
right oh we have logged in now if you go
ahead and see resume then you will see
that select star from resume we have ID
one we have content and applicant ID is
one right so that is what we were
talking about when we talked about one
to one mapping it will just store the ID
of your applicant over here right so
here only ID will be stored inside a
database when we fetch it the applicant
also will be pulled from your database
by using this applicant ID and it will
be mapped to this particular entity
resum and when we get the response on
the console the entire applicant instead
of just getting the ID right that is
basically the mapping that is basically
the relation between your applicant and
resume right here what we are doing over
here is let me go back over here and if
you see here we are adding resume
applicant ID inside your resume right so
it is basically one directional mapping
one to one mapping unidirectional
mapping right so we are adding resume
for respective applicant what we can do
we can add resume while we are adding
applicant itself so here only we can add
resume right while adding applicant only
we add resume as well right that is B
directional mapping basically B
directional Association by directional
Association within your entities right
so let's see how to do that now right so
what I will do let's go back over here
and in applicant also we will add a
resume now right so I have added a field
for that and I will say one to one
mapping right and here we can add
something called as mapped by so mapped
by is basically which entity is mapping
it so Will just add let's say
applicant applicant is the one who is
mapping it now just by using this change
let's see what happens right so let me
just rerun this code let's see what
happens right so what we can do over
here now let's go over here and and
let's go to this body and let's add one
more field which is resume right so we
have resume as well over here and how
our resume is going to look like now the
resume will have content right so let's
add content inside resume and I'll add
some content over here let's say reu
resume right so it is kind of mongal
shu's resume over here and that is
something which we have added now so
that is how we can update our body right
now if I send it let's see what happens
right now if you see this response we
are not getting resume as such right why
we are not getting it let's let's look
at it now right so if you see here we
have added this but we did not add any
gets and sets it's a small mistake that
we made so let's do let's generate
getter and Setter for this resume as
well and let's rerun our application
right so let it start so it should be
started and let's go over here and send
it again right and guess what we are
getting an internal server error so
that's interesting let's see why we are
getting this error so if you see over
here it says transient object exception
right it says save transient instance
before flushing right that means what
exactly is happening over here is now
here if you see we are trying to save
this applicant rate but while saving
this applicant the resume is not saved
inside a database the resume that we are
passing along with this object right
this resume it is not saved inside the
database right that is why it is crying
that okay dude your resume is not stored
how I'm going to store this applicant
right so that is a problem isn't it that
is when something called as cascading
comes into picture right so there are
two ways you can solve this problem
first what you can do while saving this
applicant you can first save resume and
then save applicant right programmatic
right but there is another way as I
mentioned is by using cascading right so
what we can do over here we can go to
this applicant and what we can do over
here we can just highlight a Cascade
type we'll say Cascade and we'll say
Cascade type all that means if we are
adding applicant then first resume will
get added and after that this applicant
will get added right same with delete
same with delete as well so if you are
deleting applicant first resume will be
deleted and then applicant will be
deleted so it is kind of a cascading
that we are doing over over here right
so if you go inside casket type there
are many casket type right so all is
basically which contains everything
right so we have persist that means only
persisting while persisting you add
right so in that case remove will not
work after that you have merge remove
refresh and detach right so you have
many option if you select all everything
will be taken care of that's why we are
selecting all over here right cant we
have updated we have added this
particular casket type now let's rerun
our code and let's see what happens
right this time so let it run so it's up
and running and now let's try to send
again we are getting internal server
error let's see what is the problem this
time right so here if you carefully
observe we are getting error as property
value exception right property value
exception over here which says not null
property references a null or transient
value right where where exactly it is
crying it crying inside resume right so
what exactly is happening over here if
you see over here so when we are doing
mapping over here in applicant right we
are giving nullable as false that means
this applicant ID cannot be null right
but when we are using casket type all
over here it is first trying to insert
resume at that moment applicant is not
inserted in the database so your resume
is not aware what exactly is the value
of your applicant right or what exactly
is applicant ID over here right so that
is a problem over here right so in order
to address that what we can do over here
let's go to applicant service and before
adding our applicant what we can do over
here is we can just get a resume from
this applicant so what we'll do we'll
say applicant. getet resume right catch
it in a variables we have resume there
and what we can do over here we can say
resume
dot set applicant so we are setting this
applicant up front to this resume right
so like that before that we can just add
a simple null check if resume is not
null because in case if we are not
passing it from the UI it will fail
right so that's it so what we are doing
over here so as resume will be added
first because of cascade what we are
doing we are we are first adding this
applicant to this resume right so that
this null check inside resume will not
fail right this null check over here
where is it this null Lael right if I
run this code again now and uh let's see
let it come up once it is up so if you
again hit this let's see what happens
now if you see we are getting this data
but if you carefully observed you will
see that there is kind of a infinite
Loop that we are seeing over here right
what exactly is happening over here is
if you see over here so first we are
trying to print this particular
applicant right so applicant have resume
applicant have resume and inside resum
we again have applicant and inside
applicant we again have resume and it is
going so on right so it is kind of a
infinite Loop right so that is kind of a
problem that we are facing over here
right so it's funny basically so if you
go back over here so this can be avoided
so this is happening because we have B
directional mapping right so we have
kind of a circular dependency right so
in know order to avoid that we can make
use of something like Json ignore right
this is basically to prevent resume to
serialize this applicant in order to
avoid the recursion that we are facing
over here right so if I stop and rerun
now let's see what happens hopefully
this time it should work there we go now
it is working smooth like a but right so
that is basically Json ignore annotation
so what all things we have seen we have
seen casket delete right so first we
have faced the problem and we have
solved it by using casket delete after
that we have faced another problem and
we have solved it by using a
programmatic approach over here inside
our applicant service right and we have
made sure that your resume have the
application ID up front because it's a
not null value after that we have faced
another problem and we have solved it by
using Json ignore right so those are the
problem you can forecast and these are
the steps you can take to solve that
problem right so that is basically how
your bir directional mapping works right
now if we go back and look into our
database let me just reload it over here
and if you look at applicant now then
you will see a normal applicant and if
you see the resume and you'll see
applicant ID is basically added right so
that is basically how it is working now
you may have a question that if you
don't have the applicant ID over here in
the database how it is working right so
hnet is basically handling these things
for us it will just pull the data
according to our entity even if it is
not stored inside our DB right it will
frame the queries accordingly right so
if we go back to this particular agenda
so we have seen this relationship
between entities we have seen type of
relationships and we have also seen one
to one right so we have covered one to
one relationship in this particular
video right so what we can do over here
is this is basically a lengthy video
already so what we can do we can cover
one too many many to one and many to
many annotations or type of
relationships in the another part of
this particular video so I will create a
second part of it in this part we have
seen what is the relationship what is
type of relationship we have seen one to
one mapping right in the next video we
will again add few more entities to our
project and we will see different type
of relationships within those rate so
there will be lot more interesting
things coming into picture when we look
into that particular video so if you
don't want to miss that follow code
snippet now so if you like this video
hit the like button don't forget to
subscribe to Cod snippet share this
video with your friends so that they
also have idea about one to one mapping
inside ring data jpa right that's it for
this video see you in the next video